Let's start with gathering.
我们先来讲数据收集
Data acquisition can happen in a variety of ways.
收集数据的方法有很多
In this case, you already acquired
在这里你已经下载了一些可用文件
the data by downloading some files that were available.
收集好了数据
In other cases, you might need to get the data from an API or scrape it from a web page.
但在其它时候 你可能需要从 API 处获取数据 或从网页中抓取数据
In many companies, they might have
许多公司可能本身就有数据库
an existing database from which you can pull data and answer questions.
你能从中调出数据来解决问题
You'll also often need to combine data from multiple different formats.
你往往还需要把多种不同格式的数据整合到一起
It's okay if some of these terms are unfamiliar to you,
如果你觉得有些术语听着很陌生 那也没关系
they'll be covered in more depth in our data
在数据整理课上我们会进一步解释它们
wrangling course which is linked in the instructor notes.
详见讲师注释中的链接
The lesson on gathering data within that course is great if you'd
数据整理课程有关数据收集的部分挺不错的
like to learn more about how to get data from a variety of sources.
如果你想进一步了解如何从各渠道获取数据的话 可以看一看
Your files are in a format called CSV which stands for a comma separated values.
你的文件格式为 CSV 也就是逗号分隔值的意思
A CSV file is a text file.
CSV 文件就是文本文件
It's similar to a spreadsheet in terms of its tabular structure.
从结构来看 它和电子表格类似 都是表结构
But if you've ever seen IF statements or other functions in your spreadsheets,
但如果你在电子表格里见过 IF 语句或其它函数
this isn't possible in CSV files.
你就知道 这些在 CSV 里是不可能出现的
They hold only the raw data.
CSV 仅存储原始数据
The contents of a CSV file are also very easy to process manually using code.
另外 你可以使用代码 很轻易地手动处理 CSV 的内容
Unlike for example, an XLSX file,
不像其它文件 如 XLSX
which is the format used by Microsoft Excel.
也就是微软 Excel 用的文件格式
Let's take a look at one of your files which contains cancer data.
我们来看看你手头的一个文件 有关癌症数据的
Here's what the file looks like in Google Spreadsheets.
在 Google 表格中 文件就像这样
There's a row for each time a tumor was
每一行记录着肿瘤每次活检的结果
extracted and columns for different pieces of information,
每一列则记录着不同的信息
such as the ID, diagnosis,
如 ID、诊断、
radius, texture, area, and smoothness.
半径、质地、面积以及光滑程度
Now, here's what the file looks like if you open it in a plain text editor.
如果你在纯文本编辑器中打开文件 就会是这样
A text editor is a program like Notepad,
文本编辑器是一种程序 如 Notepad、
Sublime or Adam, that shows exactly what's present in the file.
Sublime 或 Atom 等 它能如实呈现文件的内容
As you can see, the actual content of the file are very simple.
如你所见 文件的实际内容很简单
The header row from the spreadsheet is present as the first line of the CSV file.
电子表格的第一行就是 CSV 的第一行
The second row of the spreadsheet is the second line of the CSV file and so on.
第二行就是 CSV 的第二行 以此类推
Within each row, you'll see the first cell followed by a comma,
每一行你都能看到第一个单元格后跟着一个逗号
followed by the second cell,
之后是第二个单元格
followed by a comma and so on.
再之后又是一个逗号 以此类推
This makes CSVs very easy to process in programming languages like Python
这样的文件结构使得 Python 等编程语言能够很轻易地处理 CSV 文件
and packages such as Pandas have specific functions for loading data from CSVs.
Pandas 等程序包也具备一些特定函数 能从 CSV 处加载数据